Dimitrios Kontoulis

Senior Programmer

Summary

Motivated with an innovative mind, with years of experience working as a programmer in fast growing companies, always a crucial member of the team, that has a word for the architecture of the project, and a track record of incorporating complex requirements into best solutions.

OpenSource Projects

RabbitMQ Laravel

A Laravel package to work along with RabbitMQ queue management system, wrapped in a service to be as easy as possible to use.

Rabbit Manager (Standalone)

Rabbit Manager is a standalone php package to easily manage RabbitMQ for terminal applications (it can be also used in any PHP application)

NeoEloquent (forked from Vinelab/NeoEloquent 1.4)

Neo4j Graph Eloquent Driver for Laravel. Forked and updated to work well with laravel 5.5 . Fixed many issues of the original package, added features.

I have also working forks of other popular laravel packages, in order to work with NeoEloquent, like laravel-datatables and l5-repository

CI Form Generator (Legacy)

A Codeigniter Library for auto form generation through the form validation set of rules.

More Contributions

Work experience

Senior Programmer Turbado GMBH remote R&D

Software Engineer ClickMedia Greece R&D

Web Developer SomWeb Jul 2014 - Nov 2015

Feb 2016 - today

Oct 2012 - Mar 2014



Skills

Expert in:

- PHP
- Laravel
- MySQL
- Linux
- RabbitMQ

Good level at:

- Javascript
- jQuery
- Neo4i
- MongoDb
- CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, HTML5

- AWS
- Amazon MWS

Have also worked with:

- Codeigniter
- Joomla
- WHMCS
- Magento
- Wordpress
- ElasticSearchJava (also for mobile apps)
- Python

Familiar with (used for my own side projects):

- Node.js
- AngularJS
- ExpressJS
- React
- Arduino
- 0
- C#

Tools

- PhpStorm
- Git
- Ubuntu
- Trello
- Slack
- Jira

Education

Computer Science & Telecommunications, Technological 2005 - 2010 Institute of Thessaly, Greece

Courses:

- Programming basics (C)
- Object Oriented Programming (Java, C++, C#)
- Web Programming (PHP, JavaScript)
- Network Security & Administration
- Distributed Systems in Java
- Distributed Systems in Python
- Database Development (MySQL)
- IJMI
- Analysis and Design of Information Systems
- Data Structures
- Computer Architecture
- Operating Systems
- Algorithm analysis

Interests

I enjoy composing/playing music, video games, hang out with friends and have conversasions about interesting subjects